howtodothings.com 2007-10-10

# Privacy Policy | How To Do Things.com

We are committed to protecting your privacy when you visit [HowToDoThings.com](http://www.howtodothings.com/) and its related websites (collectively, the “Website”), so we want you to know what information we collect during your visits, how we use it, and how you can update and control the use of that information. We reserve the right to amend or otherwise modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please re-visit this page occasionally to check for updates. 

* **Information We Collect**

We collect various types of information from our visitors which we use in the general administration of the Website, to improve the content and usability of the Website in order to meet our users’ needs and expectations, and to present to users of the Website more targeted advertising, products and services. Some of this information is provided to us voluntarily by the users of the Website, and other information is collected automatically through cookies or other Internet tracking technologies.

* **Information Collected Automatically  
**  
Each time you visit the Website, your browser or internet session automatically sends to us, and we automatically collect, the following types of information: 

  * Your browser, e.g., Internet Explorer, Netscape Navigator,
  * Your Internet domain, e.g., AOL, Netcom, Earthlink, etc.,
  * You computer's operating system, e.g., Windows, Macintosh, UNIX, Linux, etc.,
  * Your navigation path, i.e., the URLs of where you come to our site from, which of our pages you visit, and where you go as your leave (sometimes called “clickstream data”),
  * Your computer’s IP Address, and
  * A date/time stamp. 

This information is automatically stored in log files, and helps us analyze trends with regard to use of the Website so we can make the Website more useful. For example, we use this information to track how users are finding the Website, track users’ movements around the Website, determine which pages are visited the most often, and gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. However, this information does not identify individual users. 

* **Information You Provide to Us Voluntarily**

In addition, when you register as a Contributor and set up an account on the Website, we collect certain personal information, such as your first and last name and e-mail address. However, even if you do not register as a Contributor, from time to time, we may collect information that you choose to provide to us. For instance, you may provide us with personal information when:

  * Requesting additional information from us or our advertisers,
  * Submitting questions, opinions, or other feedback regarding the Website, or
  * Participating in community or interactive features that we may provide on the Website.

Examples of personally identifiable data that you may provide to us include name, address or other location information, email address, gender, age, marital status, occupation, and other similar personal information.   
**  
**

* **How We Use Information Collected Automatically**

We use the information we automatically collect only in the general administration of the Website, and to help us improve the Website to better meet your information needs.

* **How We Use Information That You Provide to Us Voluntarily**

Your e-mail address will be used _**only**_ in the following circumstances:

  * If a user of the Website has registered and been accepted as a Contributor, we may send notifications to the Contributor relating to the use of the Website or the article submission, editorial, or publication processes; 
  * Provided such Contributor has given us permission to do so, we may send additional notifications of other features on the Website to the Contributor; and 
  * If a Contributor has given us permission to do so, we may send regular notifications, periodic updates, newsletters, or other news regarding the Website, our other promotions, products, or services, or our partners and their promotions, products, or services. 

If you are a Contributor or otherwise have provided your e-mail address to us when using the Website, your e-mail address will never be shared with or displayed to any other person without your prior consent. For a description of how a user’s permission or consent is given, see “Opt-in/Opt-out Procedures” below.

We will use the other personal information you have voluntarily provided to us for marketing purposes _**only**_ with your prior permission. Otherwise, all personally identifiable information you provide is maintained in confidence. 

Except as explained above, or where you are expressly informed otherwise, we will not sell, rent, share, trade or give away any of your personal information, unless required by law, when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on the Website, or for the protection of a Contributor’s use of the Website or participation in the publication process. However, we _**will**_ share certain aggregate Website usage information or other aggregated demographic information about users of the Website in a _**non-personally identifiable**_ manner with advertisers, partners, and other third parties in order to present to users of the Website more targeted advertising, products and services. In such situations we will _**never**_ disclose information that would personally identify you. 

* **Opt-in/Opt-out Procedures**

If you become a Contributor or otherwise provide your e-mail address to us, we provide you the opportunity to “opt-out” of having your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information. For example, if a Contributor registers or signs up for a promotion, contest, or other feature provided through the Website, but does not wish to receive any additional marketing material from us, the Contributor can indicate his or her preference on the applicable registration or personal profile page.

If a Contributor no longer wishes to receive any of our notifications, updates, newsletters or promotional communications, he or she may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each of such communications or on his or her personal profile page.

You will be notified when your personal information is collected by any third party that is not our agent or service provider, so you can make an informed choice as to whether or not to share your information with that party.  
 **  
**

* **Our Security Measures**

The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

If you have any questions about security on the Website, you can email us at _admin@howtodothings.com_.

* **Why We Use “Cookies”**

A “cookie” is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site, and we link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site.

We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close you browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” or “options” file. 

If you are a Contributor, we may set a persistent cookie to store your e-mail address or password, so you don’t have to enter it more than once. Persistent cookies also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on the Website. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site, such as promotions, contests, or surveys, will be limited. 

Some of our business partners (for example, advertisers) use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies. This Privacy Policy covers _**only**_ the use of cookies by us on the Website and does not cover the use of cookies by any of our business partners. See “Third Party Advertisers” below. 

* **Third Party Advertisers  
**  
The ads appearing on the Website are delivered to users by our advertising partner, who is a reputable, independent ad server. We share Website usage information about users with our advertising partner for the purpose of targeting our advertisements on the Website. 

Our advertising partner uses cookies on the Website, which allow it to recognize a user cookie when he or she visits the Website. The information that our advertising partner collects and shares through this technology is not personally identifiable. 

For more information about our third-party advertiser, or to learn more about the choices available to you regarding this anonymous information, please click [here](http://www.google.com/privacy.html).

* **Links to Other Sites  
**  
The Website contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by us. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware of when you leave the Website and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. 

This privacy statement applies only to information collected by the Website.  
 **  
**

* **Access to Personally Identifiable Information  
**  
If you are a Contributor, and your personally identifiable information changes or you no longer desire to contribute to the Website or use any other feature offered to Contributors through the Website, you may correct, update, or delete such information or deactivate your Contributor account by making the change on “My Profile” page, by emailing our Customer Support, or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below. 
* **Website Users Located Outside of the United States of America  
**  
We have made an effort to protect the personal information of all users of the Website, and to the extent applicable, we attempt to comply with local data protection and consumer rights laws. If you are unsure whether this Privacy Policy is in conflict with the applicable local rules where you are located, you should not submit your personal information to the Website. **IN ADDITION, IF YOU ARE LOCATED WITHIN THE EUROPEAN UNION, YOU SHOULD NOTE THAT YOUR INFORMATION WILL BE TRANSFERRED TO THE UNITED STATES, THE LAWS OF WHICH MAY BE DEEMED BY THE EUROPEAN UNION TO HAVE INADEQUATE DATA PROTECTION** (see, for example, European Union Directive 95/46/EC of 24 October 1995, a copy of which can be found [here](http://europa.eu.int/eur-lex/lex/LexUriServ/LexUriServ.do?uri=CELEX:31995L0046:EN:HTML)). If you are located in a country outside of the United States of America, and you submit personal information to the Website, we will consider such submission to be your consent to the general use of such information as provided in this Privacy Policy and to the transfer of that information to and/or storage of that information in the United States of America.  
 **  
**
* **Business Transitions  
**  
In the event that we go through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred. Where feasible, you will be notified via e-mail of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information. However, we reserve the right to notify you of any such change by prominently posting a notice on the Website for 30 days after any such change. 
* **Changes in This Privacy Policy  
**  
If we decide to change this Privacy Policy, we will post those changes in the currently available version of this Privacy Policy, on the Website’s homepage, and any other place we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this Policy, we will notify you as described above.

* **Contact Us  
**  
If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our Privacy Policy, please contact us at: _admin@howtodothings.com_. 
* **Definitions  
**  
 _ **IP (Internet Protocol) Address**_  
This is the address of a computer attached to a TCP/IP network. Every client and server station must have a unique IP address. Client workstations have either a permanent address or one that is dynamically assigned for each dial-up session. IP addresses are written as four sets of numbers separated by periods; for example, 204.171.64.2. 

_**Browser Session**_  
A browser session is defined as the period of time a browser is in consecutive use. The session begins when you open the browser and ends when you close it. When you reopen the browser, you begin a new session.

_**URL (Uniform Resource Locator)**_  
An Internet address. URLs are used to locate sites on the Internet and to navigate between sites and pages within sites.
